Martha Graham Collection
Music Division, Library of Congress
- Realia (Box 389-397)
  - Awards and Honorary Degrees (Box 389-395)
    - The State of Tennessee by Lamar Alexander, Governor. Honorary Citizen of Tennessee, 1986 November 26 (Box 394)
    - Certificate of Honor, the Board of Supervisors, City and County of San Francisco, 1976 March 15 (Box 394)
    - Doctor of Humane Letters, Bard College, 1952 (Box 394)
    - Doctor of Arts, Harvard University (damaged), 1960 June 26 (Box 395)
    - Doctor of Arts, Yale University (damaged), 1971 (Box 395)
    - To: Martha Graham, 1986 National Honor. From: Dance/USA, 1986 (Box 395)
    - Night Journey selected for exhibition at the Fifteenth International Edinburgh Film Festival, 1961 August 20 – September 3 (Box 395)
    - To: Martha Graham, Conservator of the Arts. From: American Conservatory Theatre, undated (Box 395)
    - To: Martha Graham, Life Membership in The Actors’ Fund of America, 1985 April 25 (Box 395)
    - To: Martha Graham, Citation for Distinguished and Exceptional Service. From: John V. Lindsay, Mayor of the City of New York, undated (Box 395)
    - Citation to Martha Graham from the State of New York, Hugh L. Carey, Governor, 1981 January 30 (Box 395)
    - City of Pittsburgh, Sophie Masloff, Mayor, Proclaims Martha Graham Day, 1989 January 30 (Box 395)
    - Martha Graham elected to American Honorary Membership, American Academy and Institute of Arts and Letters, 1983 (Box 395)
    - Diploma Medalha do Mérito Artístico de Dança, 1989 (Box 395)
  - Artwork--Miscellaneous (Box 396)
    - [Artwork, miscellaneous items, etc.] (Box 396)
  - Realia (Box 397)
    - Blue/white handkerchief with embroidered “G” Airmail envelope marked “Rubies” Japanese scarf Eight silver or silver-plate spoons; Four bar implements Martha Graham Center of Contemporary Dance blank stationery Beaded and metal-ornamented hat (Box 397)
Bibliography
For further information on the life and work of Martha Graham, please consult the following sources:
Graham, Martha. Blood Memory. New York, 1991.
Helpern, Alice. The Technique of Martha Graham. Dobbs Ferry, New York, 1994.
Jowitt, Deborah. “Martha Graham,” in International Encyclopedia of Dance, vol. 3, pp. 209-222. New York, 1998.
Leatherman, Leroy. Martha Graham: Portrait of The Lady as an Artist. New York, 1966.
McDonagh, Don. Martha Graham. New York, 1973.
Index of Composer Names
Arma, Paul (Imre Weisshaus)
Barber, Samuel
Bartók, Béla
Bloch, Ernest
Chávez, Carlos
Copland, Aaron
Corigliano, John
Crumb, George
Dello Joio, Norman
Diamond, David
Egge, Klaus
El-Dabh, Halim
Engel, Lehman
Fine, Vivian
Gershwin, George
Green, Ray
Hindemith, Paul
Horst, Louis
Hovhaness, Alan
Johnson, Hunter
Kupferman, Meyer
Lester, Eugene
Lloyd, Norman
McBride, Robert
Menotti, Gian Carlo
Nielsen, Carl
Nordoff, Paul
Ornstein, Leo
Panufnik, Andrzej
Persichetti, Vincent
Poulenc, Francis
Ribbink, Thomas
Riegger, Wallingford
Satie, Erik
Schuman, William
Seter, Mordecai
Starer, Robert
Stravinsky, Igor
Surinach, Carlos
Tarenghi, Enrico
Toch, Ernst
Varèse, Edgard
Webern, Anton
Zamfir, Gheorghe
Index of Performer Names
Asakawa, Takako
Barnes, Thea Nerissa
Biracree, Thelma
Birch, Patricia
Brown, Charles
Brown, David
Buglisi, Jacqulyn
Butler, Ethel
Butler, John
Capucilli, Terese
Carter, William
Chao, Jessica
Chase, David
Cohan, Robert
Cohen, Moss
Cole, Miriam
Cunningham, Merce
Dakin, Christine
Delamo, Mario
Dudley, Jane
Eilber, Janet
Fein, Richard
Fisher, Juliet
Flier, Frieda
Fonaroff, Nina
Foreman, Donlin
Garay, Judith
Giovanola, Sophie
Graff, Ellen
Graham, Martha
Gray, Diane
Gutelius, Phyllis
Hart, Diana
Hawkins, Erick
Hinkson, Mary
Hochoy, David
Hodes, Linda
Hodes, Stuart
Homsey, Bonnie Oda
Horan, Robert
Kanda, Akiko
Kennedy, Angela
Kimura, Yuriko
Kuch, Richard
Lang, Pearl
Lapsezon, Noemi
Littleford, Julian
Lyman, Peggy
Macdonald, Betty
Maloney, Daniel
Marchowsky, Marie
Maslow, Sophie
Mazia, Marjorie
McDonald, Gene
McGehee, Helen
McLain-Smith, Susan
Mitchell, Lucinda
Monte, Elisa
Morin, Jean-Louis
Newton, Eric
Nureyev, Rudolf
O’Donnell, May
Parkes, Ross
Powell, Robert
Randazzo, Peter
Rioult, Pascal
Robinson, Chase
Rooks, Steve
Ross, Bertram
Ruddy, Jeanne
Sabin, Evelyn
Salvatori, Philip
Shawn, Ted
Sparling, Peter
Stevens, Nancy
Stewart, Gregory
Taylor, Paul
Terborgh, Bert
Tetley, Glen
Thompson, Clive
Turney, Matt
Tyers, Sharon
Wagoner, Dan
Walker, David Hatch
Washington, Shelley
Weidman, Charles
Wengerd, Tim
White, George, Jr.
White, Larry
Winter, Ethel
Wood, David
Wood, Marni
Yu, Henry
Yuriko [Yuriko Kikuchi]